Hi guys,
welcome back to our listening course.
In the previous lesson, we learned how to
handle form-filling questions to achieve maximum scores.
In this lesson, we're going to practice another
type, multiple choice questions, which is a bit more difficult.
These questions often appear in section 2 and section 3.
To be more specific, we're going to learn
steps for multiple choice questions and how to
boost your score when doing this type in
IELTS listening.
In this lesson, we are going to review
the formats and key features of multiple choice
question type in the IELTS listening test part 2.
Learn to distinguish between single answer and multiple
answer multiple choice questions and apply effective steps
to answer each question type.
Develop skills to spot and avoid common distractors
in this question type.
Practice predicting paraphrases and synonyms to recognize correct
answers even when different wording is used in
the audio.
And finally, apply strategies to read questions quickly,
less selectively, evaluate options, and select answers confidently
under exam conditions.
By the end of this lesson, you'll feel
more confident to tackle multiple choice questions in
part 2 of the IELTS listening test.
So, let's get started.
Multiple choice questions have two types, multiple choice
questions with single answer and multiple choice questions
with multiple answers.
These two types often appear in both section
2 and section 3, but our lesson today
just focuses on multiple choice questions in section 2.
For multiple choice questions in section 3, we'll
learn it in the next video.
In terms of difficulty level, we can say
that multiple choice questions with multiple answers are
more challenging than multiple choice questions with single answer.
Moreover, multiple choice questions in section 2 are
easier than those in section 3.
The reason is that in section 2, you
listen to only a speaker, while in section
3, you often listen to a conversation between two people.
Here are the steps for multiple choice questions.
Step one, read questions and all options.
Before listening, you should read the questions and
the options.
In section 2, there is often only one
speaker and distractors will be included in the
given options.
You have to identify which information is correct
and which may distract you from the correct one.
Step two, underline keywords.
In step two, you will underline the keywords.
This can help you locate which part the
speaker is talking about.
Guys, pay attention to the keywords that help
you identify the difference between the options.
I'll explain this in detail in the practice section.
Step 2.1, predict paraphrases.
In addition, you will have to predict some
paraphrases of the keywords, so you can listen
in an active way.
Step 3, while listening, please move your mouse
cursor or pen to the option being mentioned
and take notes next to it.
Because there is only one speaker, except for
one correct answer, all other options are distractors.
Please note that the options might not come
in order as the information in the recording.
Step 4.
After listening, you have to choose the correct
answer and never leave your answer sheet blank.
Let's move to the practice.